{
    "id": "3f79a5642db242b38c9d2054f3cb4f6c",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The man complained that he ………………………….",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, we need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is robbed",
                "has been robbed",
                "had been robbed"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me if she ………………………….. use my laptop.",
            "description": "Could is the past tense of can. When the main verb is in the past tense, we need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I want to know why you ………………………. to me.",
            "description": "Use do with you. In the simple present tense, we make questions and negatives with do and does.",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't talk",
                "don't talk",
                "not talk"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for hours but she …………………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't turned up",
                "doesn't turn up",
                "didn't turn up"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. a little faster, you could overtake her.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could / might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "run",
                "ran",
                "have run",
                "had run"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is time you …………………………… blaming others for your failures.",
            "description": "After it is time, a past tense is used with a present or future meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "stop",
                "stopped",
                "have stopped"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish I ……………………………. fly.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What will you do if you …………………………….. that job?",
            "description": "In type 1 conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will / can / may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "don't get",
                "didn't get",
                "hadn't got"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "By next September, I …………………………… in this college for twenty years.",
            "description": "We use the future perfect to say that an activity will have completed by a certain point of time in future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will teach",
                "would teach",
                "will have taught"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked her what she …………………………. there.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is doing",
                "was doing",
                "has been doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………………….. the job by next Monday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will finish",
                "will be finishing",
                "will have finished"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………….. ill for two months, before he died.",
            "description": "Perfect tenses are more common with the time expressions for and since. We use the past perfect to talk about the earlier of two past events. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}